<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on RebelCon</title>
    <link>/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on RebelCon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence for Analysis of Medical Data from Newborn Infants</title>
      <link>/talks/alison-oshea-ai-for-analysis-of-medical-data-from-newborn-infants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/alison-oshea-ai-for-analysis-of-medical-data-from-newborn-infants/</guid>
      <description>The volume of medical data being collected is continuously increasing as technology improves while the time and expertise required to analyse it is consistently scarce. Globally there is a critical shortage of radiologists to analyse scans and neurophysiologists to analyse EEG (brain-waves). At the INFANT research centre in University College Cork we are using artificial intelligence to develop tools which can analyse medical signals and scans to identify and quantify anomalies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a startup in a startup</title>
      <link>/talks/padraig-obrien-startup-in-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/padraig-obrien-startup-in-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>Building a startup in a startup, the journey of building a new product for a company that already has a successful product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building security into your workflow with InSpec </title>
      <link>/talks/mandi-walls-building-security-into-your-worflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/mandi-walls-building-security-into-your-worflow/</guid>
      <description>InSpec is an open source testing framework for infrastructure with a human- and machine-readable language for specifying compliance, security, and policy requirements. Using a combination of command-line and remote-execution tools, InSpec can help you keep your infrastructure aligned with security and compliance guidelines on an ongoing basis, rather than waiting for and then remediating from arduous annual audits.
InSpec’s flexibility makes it a key tool choice for incorporating security into a complete continuous delivery workflow, reducing the risk of new features and releases breaking established host-based security guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous delivery DevSecOps with Kubernetes: stay safe at the speed of light</title>
      <link>/talks/david-gonzalez-continuous-delivery-devsecops-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/david-gonzalez-continuous-delivery-devsecops-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, Continuous Delivery is a must. Nobody starts a new application without asking: how can we make deployments as painless as possible? The only answer to it is Kubernetes. Full stop. Kubernetes is the solution to 99% of the problems on a software development/deployment pipeline because it was engineered for it.
The problem with CD pipelines is the security: there are no standards for securing a CD pipeline as it is something new and security takes time to catch up with the requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Sprint</title>
      <link>/talks/perera-design-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/perera-design-sprint/</guid>
      <description>How to Solve Big Problems and Test New Ideas in Just 5 Days?
How many meetings and discussions does it take before you can be sure you have the right solution? What’s the most important place to focus your effort, and how do you start? What will your idea look like in real life? Entrepreneurs and leaders face big questions every day. Now there’s a surefire way to answer these important questions; the SPRINT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker: Our Journey to Production</title>
      <link>/talks/david-mills-docker-journey-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/david-mills-docker-journey-to-production/</guid>
      <description>Xanadu Consultancy has provided software development and support for Matchbook.com, one of the worlds largest sports betting exchanges, for the past seven years. A sports betting exchange, like a financial exchange, is a highly transactional and low latency platform. Matchbook handles over 600M requests each day with an average response time of less than 2ms. The system is a distributed, micro services architecture. Xanadu operates a number of separate development teams delivering new features to Matchbook and supporting the production platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failing by Succeeding</title>
      <link>/talks/cate-huston-failing-by-succeeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/cate-huston-failing-by-succeeding/</guid>
      <description>As individuals we - implicitly or explicitly - define success, as do teams. But how do these definitions and incentives impact how and what we build?
Let’s talk about the ways in which the dysfunctions of your organization become the dysfunctions of your product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frenemies: Strategies for UX and Product Management Alignment</title>
      <link>/talks/tristan-ogorman-strategies-for-ux-and-pm-alignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/tristan-ogorman-strategies-for-ux-and-pm-alignment/</guid>
      <description>Product Management and UX ought to have shared goals, right? Both disciplines essentially seek to build software to help customers drive business outcomes. The reality is, however, that alignment between both roles is not always complete, especially in the white heat of agile development. This can happen for various reasons and this talk will identify the major problems that can cause misalignment and strategies for dealing with them as they arise or to help avoid them entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping communities &amp; products thrive by fostering empathy</title>
      <link>/talks/sasha-romijn-helping-communities-and-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/sasha-romijn-helping-communities-and-products-thrive-by-fostering-empathy/</guid>
      <description>Empathy is a fundamental part of human interaction. When we communicate by email or at conferences, or indirectly, when we create products, events, or do a talk. However, our understanding of other people is full of error, and worse, bias. This can lead us to make communities and products that work poorly for people that are different from ourselves, introduce confusion and misunderstanding, exclude people unintentionally, and sometimes even cause harm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving fast at scale</title>
      <link>/talks/randy-shoup-moving-fast-at-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/randy-shoup-moving-fast-at-scale/</guid>
      <description>Most companies slow down as they get larger, but some actually get faster. This talk will discuss the speaker&amp;rsquo;s experiences leading high-performing engineering teams at Google, eBay, and Stitch Fix, and will discuss the organization, the processes, and the culture that can help a company move fast &amp;ndash; and even accelerate &amp;ndash; as it grows.
Modern software-service models take advantage of the great benefits in having the same team both build the software as well as operate it in production &amp;ndash; we call this DevOps, or simply &amp;ldquo;You Build It; You Run It&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source, Innovation &amp; Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>/talks/stephen-stack-open-source-innovation-and-competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/stephen-stack-open-source-innovation-and-competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Open Source Software (OSS) is a hot bed of innovation, and competitive advantage.
This talk is intended to investigate and understand how a company’s competitive advantage does not have to be based on a proprietary IP based value proposition for that company to succeed. Red Hat is well known for their success in this area, and historically proprietary companies such as Microsoft, are driving the entire software industry forward by open sourcing many of their platforms, and leading the way in open source software innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Journey To Modular UI Development</title>
      <link>/talks/david-lynam-journey-to-modular-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/david-lynam-journey-to-modular-ui/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, microservice architecture has become an extremely popular way of delivering server side features. Microservices provide the ability to deploy isolated changes reducing the fear of undesirable side effects or bugs. Another benefit to this that they allow new teams to confidently make changes to code they fully understand. This has been observed numerous times in Poppulo where we’ve had many new starts deploy code to production within hours of starting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryanair&#39;s Agile Journey</title>
      <link>/talks/jerry-osullivan-ryanair-agile-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/jerry-osullivan-ryanair-agile-journey/</guid>
      <description>Ryanair is a true Irish Success story and over the past 5 years it has made technology a central tenant in it’s future as it has grown it’s Ryanair Labs function to power the future of the airline. Hear how coordinating multiple teams in multiple locations is only possible with modern software engineering practices . The talk will give a sneak peek into Ryanair and Ryanair Labs. Learn how we deliver change at a rapid pace and how we are influencing the wider organisation to embrace agile as he make the journey to become the amazon of travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Technology and Orgnizations Together</title>
      <link>/talks/randy-shoup-scaling-technology-and-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/randy-shoup-scaling-technology-and-organizations/</guid>
      <description>Successful Internet companies are built on a foundation of excellent culture, efficient organization, and solid technology. As a company needs to scale, all of these parts of the foundation need to grow and scale with it. This tutorial will provide a deep dive into modern best practices at innovative companies in Silicon Valley for scaling culture, organization, and technology.
Driven primarily by the presenter&amp;rsquo;s experience ranging from small Valley startups to Google and eBay, we will learn about:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart buildings and smart cities</title>
      <link>/talks/eric-thiebaut-george-smart-buildings-smart-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/eric-thiebaut-george-smart-buildings-smart-cities/</guid>
      <description>Is IoT a fad or is it the new tomorrow?
Smart buildings are connected buildings where distinct services such as badge scanners, temperature sensors, catering and other devices and services are all interconnected in order to enhance the value of the building, reduce cost, and offer a better working environment. Similarly, smart cities aim to fluidity traffic, reduce congestion, improve energy efficiency,… in order to provide a superior living environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Board Whisperer</title>
      <link>/talks/gary-fleming-the-board-whisperer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/gary-fleming-the-board-whisperer/</guid>
      <description>At this point in Agile’s lifecycle, many teams have switched to using a Kanban Board. Some are simple, three-column trackers; others are considerably more involved. Yet, many teams don’t know how to stop for a moment and listen to their board. It’s gently trying to nudge them about the changes that it needs to make them a better team. Come along and learn how we can go from simple to just complicated enough, smoothly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Build Trap</title>
      <link>/talks/melissa-perri-build-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/melissa-perri-build-trap/</guid>
      <description>Are you building what your customers want, or are you just building?
Many companies confuse being busy with producing value, falling into a dangerous place called &amp;ldquo;The Build Trap&amp;rdquo;. They focus more on the motions of shipping feature after feature, without stopping to validate it’s what customer truly want and need. This is due in part to poor understanding of Product Management.
In order to get get out of the Build Trap and become a successful product-led organization, companies need to use strategy, process, principles, and practices to create an environment that focuses on outcomes for the user and the business rather than outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript Deep Dive</title>
      <link>/talks/matija-grcic-typescript-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/matija-grcic-typescript-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>TypeScript is Microsoft’s answer to working large, complex JavaScript code-bases, bringing static typing and EcmaScript 6 features to current browsers. In this talk, you’ll learn how TypeScript was designed to extend and embrace JavaScript idioms and how it will help you out to ensure correct code and behavior.
We will also cover how to use advanced static types in practice by explaining how the compiler analyzes control flow to determine the most specific type for a variable at any given location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Automation in Agile Testing</title>
      <link>/talks/richard-bradshaw-valuable-automation-agile-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/richard-bradshaw-valuable-automation-agile-testing/</guid>
      <description>When talking about testing, hearing the word automation usually means automated tests, to some they are synonyms. But not to Richard Bradshaw. In his eyes Automation is integral to delivering software and even more so in delivering quality software. During this workshop, we’re going to discuss and explore ways we can use Automation to support our testing efforts far beyond automated checks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome failure! - Easier said than done!</title>
      <link>/talks/sabine-wojcieszak-welcome-failure-easier-said-than-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/sabine-wojcieszak-welcome-failure-easier-said-than-done/</guid>
      <description>In the agile world we find a lot of slogans around the topic of failure: &amp;ldquo;Welcome failure&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;fail fast&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Fail early&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Fail often&amp;rdquo; are used regularly. And in theory we all agree that we can learn from failure. Some of us are also dreaming of a Blameless Culture.
But then daily business chatches us up&amp;hellip; The search for the guilty person starts as well as the finger pointing procedure! Everyone can breathe a sigh of relief not being identified as the originator of a failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is This Cloud Native Thing Anyway?</title>
      <link>/talks/sam-newman-cloud-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 18:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/sam-newman-cloud-native/</guid>
      <description>Sam has found himself spending much of the past few years dealing with buzzword-heavy areas of technology, trying to come to terms with what it all means. From DevOps, to Microservices, serverless and now Cloud Native. So many of these terms mean different things to different people. In an effort to try and set us up with a common understanding of what Cloud Native is, Sam will be taking us on a whistle-stop tour through the history leading up to Cloud Native, and try and synthesise what it is, and why it’s important.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>