<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on RebelCon</title>
    <link>/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on RebelCon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Sprint</title>
      <link>/talks/perera-design-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/perera-design-sprint/</guid>
      <description>How to Solve Big Problems and Test New Ideas in Just 5 Days?
How many meetings and discussions does it take before you can be sure you have the right solution? What’s the most important place to focus your effort, and how do you start? What will your idea look like in real life? Entrepreneurs and leaders face big questions every day. Now there’s a surefire way to answer these important questions; the SPRINT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Journey To Modular UI Development</title>
      <link>/talks/david-lynam-journey-to-modular-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/david-lynam-journey-to-modular-ui/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, microservice architecture has become an extremely popular way of delivering server side features. Microservices provide the ability to deploy isolated changes reducing the fear of undesirable side effects or bugs. Another benefit to this that they allow new teams to confidently make changes to code they fully understand. This has been observed numerous times in Poppulo where we’ve had many new starts deploy code to production within hours of starting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Technology and Orgnizations Together</title>
      <link>/talks/randy-shoup-scaling-technology-and-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/randy-shoup-scaling-technology-and-organizations/</guid>
      <description>Successful Internet companies are built on a foundation of excellent culture, efficient organization, and solid technology. As a company needs to scale, all of these parts of the foundation need to grow and scale with it. This tutorial will provide a deep dive into modern best practices at innovative companies in Silicon Valley for scaling culture, organization, and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Build Trap</title>
      <link>/talks/melissa-perri-build-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/melissa-perri-build-trap/</guid>
      <description>Are you building what your customers want, or are you just building?
Many companies confuse being busy with producing value, falling into a dangerous place called &amp;ldquo;The Build Trap&amp;rdquo;. They focus more on the motions of shipping feature after feature, without stopping to validate it’s what customer truly want and need. This is due in part to poor understanding of Product Management.
In order to get get out of the Build Trap and become a successful product-led organization, companies need to use strategy, process, principles, and practices to create an environment that focuses on outcomes for the user and the business rather than outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new manager survival guide</title>
      <link>/talks/cate-huston-manager-survival-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/cate-huston-manager-survival-guide/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuable Automation in Agile Testing</title>
      <link>/talks/richard-bradshaw-valuable-automation-agile-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 12:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/richard-bradshaw-valuable-automation-agile-testing/</guid>
      <description>When talking about testing, hearing the word automation usually means automated tests, to some they are synonyms. But not to Richard Bradshaw. In his eyes Automation is integral to delivering software and even more so in delivering quality software. During this workshop, we’re going to discuss and explore ways we can use Automation to support our testing efforts far beyond automated checks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is This Cloud Native Thing Anyway?</title>
      <link>/talks/sam-newman-cloud-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 18:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/sam-newman-cloud-native/</guid>
      <description>Sam has found himself spending much of the past few years dealing with buzzword-heavy areas of technology, trying to come to terms with what it all means. From DevOps, to Microservices, serverless and now Cloud Native. So many of these terms mean different things to different people. In an effort to try and set us up with a common understanding of what Cloud Native is, Sam will be taking us on a whistle-stop tour through the history leading up to Cloud Native, and try and synthesise what it is, and why it’s important.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>